                                                                        Unit 27 Text features 1



Collocations           This refers to groups of words which go together. See the Words and Phrases
                       section for work on these.
Problems with          Some words which end in -s are singular:
plurals                   the news a means
                       In adjectival phrases involving numbers, nouns are singular: 
                          a three-mile walk a ten-year-old child

                    Activities
1                   Practice in this unit is with texts which have single words missing. See Units 28 
Put one word in     and 29 for other kinds of practice. Note that the activities are not simply a test 
each space.         of the points made in this unit.

                    Starting your (1)        business could be the way to achieving financial
                    independence, or (2)        could just as well land you in debt for the rest of
                    your life. That, at (3)     , is the view of Charles and Brenda Leggat, a
                    Scottish couple, who last week saw (4)       fish farm business put into the
                    hands of the receiver. 'We started the business in 1985 when (5)   was
                    being encouraged by the banks to borrow money. (6)        the time we were
                    sure that we could make (7)        into a going concern,' said Charles Leggat,
                    a farmer from (8)        Highlands, 'and the banks lent us more or less
                    (9)         we asked for. Their people analysed the proposals we put
                    (10)         , and they agreed that it would be a highly profitable business.'
                    Sure (11)        , within five years the Leggats were exporting trout and
                    salmon products to hotels (12)       over Europe, and employed over fifty
                    staff. But with the advent (13)      the recession, they began to lose ground
                    as orders dried up. The awful thing (14)      said Brenda Leggat, 'that 
                    now the business has been valued by the banks at a fraction of its true worth. If 
                    they had left us to work our way out of our difficulties I am sure that we could
                    have gone back into profit. (15)     it is, we have been left (16)     a
                    livelihood, and the banks have not recovered (17)      they lent us.' The
                    Leggats both felt that their banks had not treated (18)   fairly. 'They
                    were falling over (19)      to lend us the money, but they have done very
                    little to keep the business going, and fifty local people (20) work.' A
                    spokesman for the main bank concerned, the National Caledonian, refused to 
                    comment.

2                   Recently there have been doubts about the proper functioning of the English
Put one word in     legal system, after several well-publicised cases in (1)  police evidence
 each space.        was eventually shown to be suspect, but (2)      after the wrongful
                    conviction of the accused. In several of (3)    cases, the crimes involved
                    acts of terrorism, and the police were (4)     considerable pressure to
                    discover (5)         had been responsible. Although this in no way excuses
                    the actions of police officers (6)     may have falsified evidence, or


                                              153

